Black Beans and Rice from “A Taste of Old Cuba”, by Maria Josefa LLuria de O'Higgins.

8 Servings

Ingredients: 1. For cooking the beans:

1 pound dry black beans

2.5 quarts water

1 green bell pepper, cored, seeded and cut into strips

2 garlic cloves, peeled and lightly crushed but left whole

1 large slice of onion (optional)

2. To complete the dish:

One third cup Spanish olive oil

2 medium onions, peeled and finely chopped

1 large green pepper, cored, seede and finely chopped

6 garlic cloves, peeled and minced

1 teaspoon salt

Half teaspoon freshly ground blavk pepper

Half teaspoon ground cumin

Half teaspoon dry leaf oregano

1 bay leaf

1 tablespoon raw or brown sugar

2 tablespoons red or white wine vinegar

Soak and Cook the beans:

1. Place the beans in a colander and rinse them under cold running water. Pick over them to remove small stones and debris.
2. Transfer the beans to a large pot, cover them with the water, and soak for at least 8 hours (i.e. overnight).
3. Add the green pepper, garlic and onion to the pot and bring it to a boil.
4. Skim the espuma or foam off the surface of the liquid periodically; lower the heat to medium, cover and cook the beans till they are tender,
   approximately 1 hour. Remove the green pepper and onion slices and discard.

To Complete the Dish:

1. While the beans are cooking, make the sofrito: warm the oil over medium heat in a large heavy skillet. Saute the onions and green pepper until the onions are translucent, about 3 to 5 minutes. Stir in the garlic, salt, cumin, pepper and oregano, and cook for 2 to 3 minutes more.
2. Remove this sofrito from the heat and place in a food processor or blender, along with 1 to 2 ladlefuls of black beans. Pulse until pureed.
3. Stir the sofrito puree, the bay leaf and the sugar into the beans. bring the beans to a boil again. ;lower the heat and simmer uncovered till the cooking liquid has the consistency of thick gravy. Stir frequently so that the beans do not stick to the bottom of the pot.
4. Just before serving, remove the bay leaf, stir in the vinegar, and if desired, a little more olive oil. Serve over white rice, topped if desired with vinegar and chopped raw onion.

Garden: Plantings 2008

2007 or 2008: Corylus avellana 'contorted', “Harry lauder's Walking stick”, by garage, next to walkway to garden. 2007 or 2008, planted 2 Honeysuckle,”halls”, on either side of back porch stairs. (Direct Gardening). By 2009, they are covering the trellises there and are cold hardy. Many perfumed flowers in Spring.

2008, Dwarf Patio Peach, grown by Holland Nursery, Franklin, VA; (Harris teeter), by walkway to garden. Hardy zone 5 to 9.

* 3-07? 4 rosebushes in front of garage: “Carefree Delight”, 45102; spacing 5', Height 4', full sun, Bloom time late spring to mid fall; from park catalog. Bought the previous fall, wintered over in pots in yard. 4-10-09 applied Bayer Advance Garden 2-in-1 Rose and Flower Care granules, 12-8-6, (disulfaton), to bases of all roses.

2007? Fig, 'Petite negra', Ficus carica in 2 large pots by patio. Spacing 3 to 5' apart, soil average, well-drained, full sun, height 5 to 8'. Park Plants mail order.

Winter 2008? planted Pink Dogwood, #5 pot, in front yard.

* 3-13-08 Walkway edge by patio - Cilantro (coriander), Cooks Garden - Garlic Chives (Chinese Leeks), Seeds of Change - Viola Johnny-Jump-Up, Viola tricolor, Botanical Interests - Thymus serpyllum (mother of thyme), Park seed *3-21-08 walkway edge on side far from house: Strawberries red and yellow Wonder Alpine, John Scheepers Kitchen Garden Seeds

*3-23-08 In field by garage: 4 Hansen's Bush Cherries from direct Gardens (also 1 Hansen's Bush in a pot) *3-24-08 Surrounding the raised bed with peach tree and mints: 9 Irish moss plants, from Direct Gardens.

  Water Lily, white, planted in pot, placed into pond.

*3-26-08 10 Stella D'oro day lilies planted on either side of path leading to garden, (Direct Gardens). *3-27-08 By southeast window corner of house, Alyssum Sweet, Rosie O'Day, Labularia maritima, and Alyssum Sweet, Oriental Nights, Lobularia maritima, (Botanical Interests).

*3-28-08 Right edge of driveway: planted Native Day Lily seedlings, in and next to daffodil bed; also added Alyssum “Carpet of Snow”, seeds. Ferry Morse. *4-05-08 edge of raised bed containing mint and peach tree: Cosmos Sensation Mixed Colors, (Ferry-Morse). Also “Triplet Lilies”, bulbs from Direct Gardening.

*4-05-08 3 oblong planters on porch: Sweet Marjoram, Heirloom, Origanum majorana, (Seeds of change); Greek Oregano, Heirloom, Origanum heracleoticum, (Seeds of Change); Lettuce Deer's Tongue, (Park Seed). *4-12-08 New raised bed, between driveway and raised bed surrounding tree: Gypsophila Snowfountain. Cook's Garden, 2007 seeds. Plan to plant again in 3 or 4 weeks, as it blooms 6 weeks from planting. Also, Flashback Calendula,Calendula officinalis, hardy annual, Seeds of Change., 2007 seeds. in bed surrounding tree, planted Rudbeckia Indian Summer, 2 packs,Cook's Garden, 2007 seeds.

*4-19-08 bed by driveway, front of apricot tree: Gypsophila Snowfountain, Cook's garden; Florists' Favorite, Yellow Sunflowers, Botanical Interests. Mixture of Apricot Twist, Lemon Sorbet, Moonshadow, Lemon Eclair,Stella, Lemon Aura, Pro Cut Orange, Peach Passion. *4-23-08 planted by front door edge of walkway: Viola plants, Etienne, from Direct Gardening. planted by edge of driveway parking space: red Gaillardia plants, Direct Gardening. 4-09 Some violas have returned and blossomed despite the clover.

*4-27-08 planted by front walkway, 4 plants of Iberis sempervirens 'Snowflake', Candytuft. 1 was gift from Erica Alexander; at edge of garden by garage; 3 plants Lavender “Fred Boutin”, 3 plants “Grosso”,alternating, closest plant to house being a Fred Boutin. Lavenders from Annie at Sunshine Lavender Farm. *4-30-08 6 “Siloam June Bug” daylilies by right edge of stairs from screened porch, from Direct Gardening; 3 Chrysole Flame Yellow, plants, by left side of stairs from porch, from Park Seed. 18 Native daylilies, by edge of driveway, Direct Gardening; 6 Iris Ensata mixed, by left edge of garden gate, from Direct Gardening.

*5-10-08 8 Stella D'oro plants by walkway edge leading to garden; Direct Gardening; Zinnia Lilliput seeds, mixed colors, Ferry-Morse Seeds; and Drop Dead Red Sunflowers, Botanical Interests; both by edge of screened porch, beside Yarrow plant (planted fall 2007, bought at SC campground Festival. *09-01-08 planted by garden path: Bee balm, dotted mint, Monarda lambada, (Botanical Interests). (Did not come up)

*10-05-08 Planted 4 Lingonberry plants in front of house, to right of front door (Stark Bros) * 1 blueberry bush, planted at edge of garden path. * Norwegian Spruce tree, bought for Christmas tree with root ball,(4 to 5 foot), to plant outside after Christmas; $78. at TROSA, at Southpoint mall 12-7-08 ===== Bulbs ===== Tulips Angelique, planted directly by garage side door next to walkway, 2-08, 12 bulbs. Iris Dutch Iris Mix, planted by walkway leading to garden, February 2008 (WFF) ===== Tulips ===== * Mrs. John T Scheepers, from White Flower farm (WFF); planted 1-08 in pots, front porch * Daffodils, from WFF, planted 1-08, next to right edge of driveway; also along edge of walkway to fenced garden. Blooming 2-20-08. * “A big batch of little alliums”, WFF, planted 11-07, right edge of front walk, by mudroom window. ===== Gladioli===== * 3-02-08 planted 25 Gladiolus grandiflorus 'Fidelio' (dark pink) and 25 Gladiolus grandiflorus 'Plumtart' (dark red) bulbs in area in front of mudroom window. (Lowes) 5-26-08** planted 20 gladioli bulbs (Direct gardening), by crawl space door; also Lupines Russell Hybrid, (Botanical Interests). 2 pkgs.

12-25-08, Chamaecyparis 'Hinoki Crippsii', evergreen, planted in front yard behind Mulley grass, 12-25-08; color: golden; spacing, 6-8 feet apart; location: sun/light shade; height: 15 to 20 feet. Wayside Gardens or Park.

12-07-08 Norwegian Spruce tree, bought for Christmas tree with root ball,(4 to 5 foot), to plant outside after Christmas; $78. at TROSA, at Southpoint mall; planted in front yard 4-12-09.

Dutch Iris combination, 75 bulbs, Iris hollandica planted next to garden path by 2 blueberry bushes. 2-21-09

3-9-09 MEDICINAL HERBS: along garden walkway

German Chamomile, Matricaria recutita, (Seeds of Change), 2 pkts

St John's Wort, Hypericum perforatum, (Seeds of Change), 2 pkts

Burnet Salad, Poterium sanguisorba, (Botanical Interests).

3-24-09 Kiwi, Meader, male, planted by living room window, next to female Issai kiwi. (Lowes).

3-24-09 Lavender, French variegated, Lavandula dentata, (J&B Plant Farms, from Whole Foods), in circle in front of yard, by driveway. Size: 15 to 18 ” tall. Zone 8-10. Full Sun.

4-12-09 Hollyhock,Indian Spring,Alcea rosea; Marigold Gem Mix, Tageters signata,(Cooks); Marigold calendula, Burpee's mixed colors, (Burpee); all by living room window surrounding the kiwis. 5-23-09, same bed, Cosmos Sensation Picotee, (Lowes); and Sunflowers, Moulin Rouge, (Kitchen Garden Seeds).6' tall.

4-19-09, 3 Dogwoods, from Brian Voyce's yard; next to the driveway.

4-19-09, 1 Japanese Maple, in front of the turret and mudroom, from Brian's yard.

4-19-09, 2 Lavender,Spanish, to the right of path to garden, by the house; from Raindrop Ridge Farm,1356 Camp Leach Road,Washington NC 2788;252-402-6017; 252-923-9251. raindropherbs@embarqmail.com.(Shakori hills Festival)

4-19-09, Bay tree, Laurel nobilis; replaced bay at right of garden path with bay from pot; then transplanted old bay to another pot since it had new growth near roots.

4-19-09, Patchouli, Pogostemon cablin, tender perennial, in pot, from Raindrop Ridge Farm. Full or part sun or place in sunny window. 36” tall.

4-25-09, Golden Euonymus aureomarginatus, Euonymus japonicus, 3 in front of house, replacing gardenias; part sun, hardy to -10F, apply mulch to overwinter, mature size 6' tall, 36” wide, space 36”, upright habit, fertilize in spring, water daily. Home Depot

4-25-09, Euonymus Dwarf Boxleaf, Euonymus japonica 'Microphylla', evergreen shrub to 2' with upright habit; sun. 2 plants in front of house. Home Depot

4-25-09, Euonymus Variegated Boxleaf, Euonymus j. 'Microphylla Variegata', dense evergreen shrub to 2', dark green leaves with white margins, Sun. 2 plants in front of house. Home Depot

Pepper, Thai Hot, ornamental pepper, full sun, maturity in 80 days, space 24” apart, fruit size 1” long. 4 plants in front of house. Home Depot.

5-2-09 Morning Glory flowers, by front stoop; Chocolate, Ipomoea nil, 2008 seed, (Botanical Interests); Morning Glory blue, 2007 seed, (Ferry Morse); Sunrise Blend, Ipomoea purpurea, 2008, (Botanical Interests).

5-4-09, by front walkway, front to back:

Alyssum, Gold Dust, Saxatile compactum,height 12 ”, sun/partial shade. Perennial. (Ferry-Morse): did not grow.

Tithonia, mexican Sunflower, 4' height, full sun. (Ferry-Morse) 10-11-09; grew well but slowly, pretty dark orange flowers, blooming in Aug to Sept.

Baby's Breath, Gypsophila paniculata, hardy perennial, 1 to 3' tall, 1/4 ” flowers, (Seeds of Change)

Sunflowers, Cutters delight Mix, 2007 seed, (Cooks Garden).

5-4-09, bed by patio, Sunflowers, Moulin Rouge, 2007 seed, (Cooks Garden). 5-4-09, bed by mints and peach tree, Echinacea purpurea, Purple Cornflower, (Wildseed Farms) seed from Fall 2008. 10-09, slowly growing, still small plants.

5-6-09 Morning Glories, Heavenly Blue, Ipomoea tricolor, 2008 seed, planted by front porch and by garden gate. (Botanical Interests)

5-17-09 bed by driveway, Wildflowers, Butterfly/Hummingbird blend, and Echinacea purpurea, (Wildseed Farms). 10-09: this blend produced mostly Cosmos, some smaller flowers, no echinacea yet but may be slow growing.

5-23-09 bed by patio, Sunflowers, Moulin Rouge, 2009 seed, (Cooks Garden).

5-24-09 bed by driveway, Rudbeckia, Indian Summer, 2007 seed, (Cooks Garden); Wildseed farms, Texas Hill Country Adventure Mix.

9-26-09 by front walkway: 2 plants, Japanese Bloodgrass (Direct Gardening).

10-10-09 By front door and turret windows; Naturalizing Lily Mixture, 984200, (White Flower Farm), 25 bulbs.

10-10-09 By driveway, in Jizo flower bed, 3 bearded iris , (White Flower farms): *

'Pagan Dance'0032568

'Cloud Ballet” 0032237

' Mother Earth' 0032568

and 3 bearded iris from (Direct Gardening)

'Edith Worford'

'Best Bet'

'Blutique'.

Also by Jizo:

Hyacinthoides hispanica 'Rose Queen', 25 bulbs. (White Flower Farm)

Allium caeruleum 303003, 25 bulbs. (White Flower Farm)

10-09 Hydrangia, (cutting from Karen Wilson), started in outdoor pot; overwintered well despite 18 degree nights, sending shoots up 2-10.

10-11-09 By front walkway: 3 bulbs, Lilium 'La Claridad', (White Flower farms).

11-09 Iris, Dutch Iris Mix, 100 bulbs, in bed by walkway to garden. Product of Holland. (White Flower Farm)

11-22-09, in 2 small pots on patio: Rose, white.

11-09 Grape Hyacinth bulbs, front by garage, (Direct Gardening).

11-22-09 Hostas, 2, “Paul's Glory”, Hosta, by garage front yard. 4-6 hours sun; hardy to -40F; size 22-25” tall by 24-36” wide; space 24 to 36'; clumping; water daily.

11-22-09 by edge of walkway in front of garage: Salvia x2, Salvia nemorosa, Sensation white, 6 hours or more of sun;' hardy to -30F; size 10-12” tall by 12-18” wide; space 18”; water weekly.

Yard Plants 2010

3-7-10:

I widened the bed by the right edge of driveway and pull-out space: planted with:

Echinacea, 'White Swan”, Echinacea purpurea cv, (Thyme garden herb Co), I did not prechill seeds as indicated, but direct seeded; we're still having 30 degree nights, so we'll see.

Black-eyed Susans, 'Indian Summer', (John Scheepers);

Black eyed Susans, 'Autumn Colors”, (John Scheepers);

Black-eyed Susans, ' Irish Spring”, (John Scheepers).

Bed by the driveway and front door walkway:

Echinacea, Purpole Coneflower, Echinacea purpurea, (Wildseed Farms, 2009).

Butterfly/Hummingbird Blend, (Wildseed Farms, 2009).

3-14-10 planted “Bells of Ireland”, Molucella laevis, by Apricot tree near driveway.

3-10 Lemon thyme, Thymus x citriodorus, by bay leaf tree on right side of walkway between house and garage.

4-10-10

Oregano 'Golden”, Oregano vulgare 'Aureum', by walkway to garden, next to small rosemary. (Plant from J&B Herb & Plant Farms Inc)

Lavender, ' Jean Davis', in front yard bed in front of Jizo (Lavender farm), 2 small potted plants

Rudbeckia x hirta, 'Cherry Brandy', in front yard by Apricot tree, (Botanical Interests, 2010).

Sunflower,'Colorful Fantasia Mixture', same bed, (John Scheepers Seeds, 2009)

Coreopsis,'Early Sunrise', same bed, (John Scheepers, 2009)

Tithonia, Mexican Sunflower, same bed, from saved seed 2009, original from Ferry-Morse.

Forget-me-Not, 'Bluebird', by front door, (Ferry Morse, 2007 seed)

Foxglove, Digitalis purpurea 'Gloxiniflora', by front door, (Botanical Interests, 2007).

5-29-10

Zinnia, “Royal Purple”, in bed by Jizo, in front yard (Baker Creek Seeds)

Zinnia, “Lilliput Mix”, same bed (Baker Creek Seeds).

Sunflower, Helianthus annuus, “Tangerine”, 2008-9 seed, next to back porch and in first black plastic bed by garden. (Wildseed farms)

Sunflower,Helianthus annuus, “Santa Fe”, in garden, near house, far garage.

5-31-10

Morning Glory, “La Vie en Rose”, by driveway, in front of apricot tree. (Baker Creek Seeds, 2009).

8-10 chamomile, by patio

2011

5-7-11 * Anise Hyssop, seed, by patio * Blue Monday sage, seed, Salvia, (Baker Creek,2010), by patio * Clary sage, seed, Salvia sclarea, (Seeds of Change, 2009 seed), by patio * Swiss Chard, Pink, by patio.

5-7-11, by driveway: * Lavender Bergamot, Monarda fistulosa, (Seeds of Change, 2008) * Poppy, Papaver (Thyme Garden, 2010) Mugwort, Artemesia vulgaris (Thyme Garden, 2010) by fireplace along edge of walkway to garden.

5-11 * Hydrangia paniculata 'Renhy' “Vanilla Strawberry” hydrangia, in front yard by driveway, (Park Seed)? 6-15-11 * Buddleia Butterfly Heaven (PPAF) ( Park Seed), 2 plants in front of house, in front of library. height 6 feet. * Rudbeckia 'Goldstrum Strain', R. fulgida, (Park Seed), 3 plants front of house, in front of guest bedroom. * Vaccinium 'Pink Lemonade', blueberries, (Park Seed), potted 4 plants, To plant in ground in the fall.

10-8-11 Bed in front of screen porch:

* Ornamental grass, Hakonechloa Macra “All Gold”, 9Burpee); Ht 5 ft, sp 18 in, Part shade. 2 plants. *From left to right: * Camassia “Blue Candle”, (Burpee), 3 bulbs, Hy 24 to 32”, blue flowers, Spring bloom, part sun or full sun, plant 18” deep, 20” apart, from Holland. * Chamomile Bodegold, (J Scheepers) 2 pkts. * Ag. mexicana “Sangria”, Lemon Hyssop, (Thyme Garden) * Iris reticulata cantab,10 bulbs, Ht 4 to 8”, blue, Spring bloom, part or full sun, from Holland (Burpee) * Reseda odorata “Mignonette, (Thyme Garden) * Onion, Egyptian Walking, 5 bulbs, ( Burpee)

10-22-11 * 4 pink blueberry bushes, previously planted on pots; bed near screen porch, central area. Vaccinium “Pink Lemonade”, (Park Seed). * Bed in front yard surrounding Jizo: Butterfly Hummingbird Wildseed mixture. * same bed: seeds from garlic chives from back yard.

11-23-11 * Lily 'Dot com' (Asiatic), 5 bulbs, bed in front of screen porch, (Van Engelen Inc)

11-24-11 * Erythronium pagoda, 20 bulbs, along house foundation (in front) by turret room and faucet. (van Engelen Inc)

11-26-11 * Allium albopilosum, 10 bulbs, by Jizo and among lemon Balm by driveway, front yard.(Van Engelen) * Iris 'Eye of the tiger”, 100 bulbs, near Jizo and behind Lemon Balm.(Van Engelen) * Iris, 'Rainbow mixture', 150 bulbs, next to back porch, in bed along garden pathway in back yard, near Jizo. (Van Engelen)

Earl Grey Sablés

Ingredients

2 tablespoons Earl Grey tea leaves

2 cups all-purpose flour

16 tablespoons unsalted butter, room temperature

3/4 cup cane sugar, divided

1/4 cup powdered sugar

3/4 teaspoon sea salt

2 egg yolks, room temperature

2 teaspoons vanilla extract

Instructions

With a coffee or spice grinder, pulse tea leaves a few times, just enough to break them down slightly. Mix into the flour. Set aside.

In a stand mixer fitted with the paddle attachment or with a hand mixer, beat butter, 1/2 cup cane sugar, powdered sugar, and sea salt on low speed for 5 minutes. Mixture should be smooth but not fluffy. Add the yolks, and when fully incorporated, the vanilla. Turn mixer off, add flour, and then mix on low just until dough comes together.

Scrape out onto a lightly floured surface, divide dough in half, and roll into even 2-inch wide logs. Wrap tightly with plastic wrap, flattening the ends and smoothing the log as you go. Chill 4 hours or more.

Preheat oven to 350 degrees F.

Set out a baking sheet, and if desired, line with parchment.

Pour remaining 1/4 cup cane sugar into a shallow bowl.

Working quickly, unwrap and slice one of the dough logs in half. Rewrap the unused half and set back on the fridge. Press log into the sugar, making sure it's well coated all the way around. With a sharp knife, cut the log into even 1/4-inch thick slices.

Arrange on prepared baking sheet. Freeze 10 minutes to re-chill dough.

Bake for 15 - 18 minutes, or until sablés have puffed up and are a deep golden hue on the bottom. Cool 5 minutes on baking sheet then remove to a wire rack to cool completely.

Repeat for remaining cookie dough. Cooled cookies will keep sealed at room temperature for a week or so.

https://brooklynsupper.com/earl-grey-sables/

Bell Pepper Fettuccine “Confetti Fettuccine”, from Elaine Tait, Knight-Ridder Newspapers (Tampa Tribune?)

1/4 cup olive oil

1 large chicken breast, skinned, boned, cut into thin strips

1 large onion, coarsely chopped, or in rings if preferred

1 sweet red bell pepper, cut in strips

1 sweet green bell pepper, cut in strips

2 cloves garlic, minced

(1/4 to 1 teaspoon red pepper flakes, per taste)

2 or 3 large ripe tomatoes, seeded and cored, diced

1 pound cooked fettuccine

freshly grated Parmesan cheese

Put water to boil for fettuccine, and cook while the rest of the recipe is cooking.

In a large pan, heat 2 tablespoons oil over medium heat. Add chicken and saute, stirring, until chicken turns white, about two minutes.

Using slotted spoon, remove chicken from pan and set aside.

Add remaining two tablespoons of oil to pan. Increase heat to medium high, and add bell peppers and onion. Stir fry to soften, about ten minutes.

Add the chicken,garlic, and pepper flakes. Cook two to three minutes. Add tomatoes and cook till warmed through, about one minute.

Toss the chicken vegetable mixture with the well drained fettuccine to blend well. Top with grated cheese.

4 to 6 servings

Butter Lettuce with nuts, bacon, cheese, egg and sherry vinaigrette

LAtimes.com 10-19-2011

Ingredients:

2 tablespoons minced shallots

2 tablespoons Spanish sherry vinegar

1 1/2 teaspoons lemon juice

1/2 teaspoon salt

1/4 teaspoon freshly ground black pepper

1/4 cup extra-virgin olive oil

6 slices thick-cut applewood-smoked bacon

1/2 cup hazelnuts

1 tablespoon hazelnut oil

salt

2 heads butter lettuce

1 tablespoon plus 1 teaspoon lemon juice

5 hard-cooked eggs

Black pepper

2 teaspoons finely chopped fresh chives

4 ounces Gorgonzola dulce

Vinaigrette: Combine the shallots,2 tablespoons vinegar,1 1/2 teaspoon lemon juice,salt and pepper in a bowl and stir to combine. Add the oil in a slow steady stream, whisking constantly to combine. Taste for seasoning.

Cook the bacon either in oven or in pan, till it is done but still chewy. Cut each strip into 4 pieces.

Scatter the hazelnuts on a baking sheet and place them in 325 oven to toast until they are golden brown and fragrant, about 12 to 15 minutes; or can pan toast them. Watch carefully so that they do not burn.

Gather nuts into a clean dish towel, after cooling, and rub them together in the towel to remove the skins. Place nuts in a small bowl,drizzle with hazelnut oil, sprinkle with a pinch of salt and toss to coat with the seasoning.

Wash and tear the lettuce into bite sized pieces; dry.

Season the lettuce with salt, drizzle 1/4 cup of the vinaigrette and the lemon juice and toss it to coat it with the dressing.

Slice the eggs with a sharp knife and lay the slices out on a cutting board. Sprinkle the slices with salt, grind pepper over them and sprinkle with chives.

To build the salad, place lettuce leaves on the bottom of platter, then place egg slices,crumbled Gorgonzola,bacon; top with hazelnuts.